乘客们  请注意
Attention, passengers...
你得把牌子举起来
You have to lift up the sign
他才看得见啊
so he can see it.
埃文
Evan.
小伙计
Hey, buddy.
见你叔叔布兰特  你不高兴吗
Aren't you excited to see your uncle Brant?
不高兴
No.
是吗
No?
我想你是高兴的
I think you are.
我知道有别的事惹你不高兴了
I think something else is making you upset.
你知道我马上要走了
You know I'm leaving soon,
因为这事不高兴没关系的
and it's okay to be upset about that,
但你还记得周六晚上咱们一起看
but, hey, do you remember what I told you
摔跤比赛时我跟你说的话吗
when we were watching wrestling on Saturday night?
记得
Yeah.
你说你和布兰特叔叔就像那对兄弟
That you and uncle Brant are like the reaper brothers.
对
That's right.
布兰特叔叔已经在场上
And uncle Brant has been in the ring
一整年了
a whole year.
现在是时候让爸爸上场了
Now it's time for daddy to tag in.
但我不在时
But while I'm away,
我要你在你叔叔身边帮他
I need you in your uncle's corner,
确保他保护你和你妈妈的安全
making sure he keeps you and your mom safe.
你能做到吗
Can you help me with that?
好的
Good.
那现在把牌子举好吧
Now let's get ready with that sign.
女士们先生们  请注意
Attention, ladies and gentlemen,
47号登机口开始登机
we are now boarding at gate 47.
就现在
Now.
布兰特  出了什么事
Brant, what happened?
上尉  请让开
Captain, please step aside.
长官  这是我弟弟
Sir, this is my brother.
到底出了什么事
What's going on?
陆军一等兵麦克林被指控犯有叛国罪
PFC Macklin has been charged with treason.
这肯定是个误会
Oh, so there's got to be some mistake.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
布兰特
Brant!
布兰特  布兰特
Brant! Brant!
总监：
zlean
陆军方面显然认为  他们是在
Army apparently thought they were clearing
清理一个反叛分子窝点
an insurgent hideout.
自从这段录像在周六被泄露后
After this was leaked on Saturday,
美联社就开始调查
the A.P. investigated.
有34名平民伤亡
34 civilian casualties.
其中有六名儿童
Six kids.
通往二楼的所有入口都会有宪兵把守
There will be MPs stationed at every entrance to the second floor,
当然还有他的病房外
as well as outside his patient room.
别  别这么安排
No. Don't do that.
每次有当兵的来餐厅
Every time there's people in uniform in the cafeteria,
他们都能插队
they get served first.
确保证件都别在显眼的地方
Make sure your IDs are clearly visible.
我会向餐饮部传达意见
I'll speak with the cafeteria staff about showing
让他们尽量一视同仁
more disrespect.
病人20岁  男性  全身性强直阵挛发作
20-year-old male, generalized tonic-clonic seizures.
军医检查了是否有结构性病变
Army docs scanned for structural abnormalities.
脑电图正常  所以...
EEG was normal. So was--
你还需要我签字吗
Do you need me to sign for this?
如果你们有什么需要  告诉我一声
Let me know if you need anything,
比如转院
like a transfer.
斑疹伤寒
Typhus?
病人是光头
Patient has no hair.
也就是说没有虱子
Probably means no lice.
利什曼病
Leishmaniasis.
他没有发热
No fever.
他们为什么不在
Why couldn't they take care of him
军队医院治疗他
at a military hospital?
我想他们就是想找你的麻烦
I think because they wanted to annoy you.
还有没有良心发现的反对者了
Any other conscientious objectors?
只有我看不惯吗
So I'm the only one
他的职责是
who has a problem when someone
保卫我们的国家  却泄露...
whose duty's to protect our country blowing--
泄露告密是十分崇高的
Blowing the whistle is honorable
正因为那并不是他的义务
precisely because it's not dutiful.
抱歉  你说到泄露
Sorry, you said blowing.
也许你是想说别的事
Maybe you were going somewhere else with that.
他是个懦夫
He's a coward.
他可是冒了失去自由的风险
He risked his freedom.
他匿名从一个安全的网页
He anonymously downloaded a computer file
下载了一个文件然后上传到
from a secure page and uploaded it
一个不安全的网站
to an unsecure page.
又不是突袭奥马哈海滩
Not exactly storming Omaha beach.
奥马哈海滩是诺曼底登陆中
四个主要登陆地点之一的代号
脑电图正常  说明他装病
The EEG was normal because he was faking it
这样就不用进监狱了
to avoid going to prison.
那咱们就用不给药治疗他
Let's treat him with not medicine.
还给我
Give those back.
为什么  有28粒呢
Why? You got 28.
分享一下没关系
You can share.
豪斯有点问题
Something's going on with House.
他有点心不在焉
He just seemed off.
都没注意到我离开房间时
Didn't even notice that I walked out
把这个带出来了
of the room with this.
你想知道他是否心不在焉  趁其不注意
You began to suspect he was off when he didn't notice
偷走了杯子  你就怀疑他确实心不在焉
the mug you stole to see if he was off?
他还没注意什么你不想让我们发现的事
What else didn't he notice that you don't want us to notice?
你昨天就穿的这身衣服
Those are the same clothes you wore yesterday.
当豪斯拿走你的避孕药时
And you got very defensive
你十分生气
when house took your birth control.
他是谁啊  或者更美好  "她"是谁
Who was he? Or better yet...she?
是需要我解释避孕药的生理学原理吗
Do I need to explain the physiology behind birth control?
一个没有注意力缺陷的人开始精力涣散
Attention deficit in a man who has no attention deficits
一定是因为某种因素引起的
has to be symptomatic of something.
你说得对  我认为要不就是一个大脑瘤
You're right. I'm thinking either massive brain tumor,
要不就是他喜欢的肥皂剧被砍了他很伤心
or his soap got canceled and he's distracted.
可能是膳食引起的  植烷酸贮积症
Could be dietary, Refsum.
或者他不过是认为
Or maybe he thinks you just have
这种大众化的白色衬衣  你有不止一件
more than one nondescript white blouse.
或者是血清素综合征
Or serotonin syndrome.
我不是说他肯定有病
I'm not saying he's definitely sick.
我只是想说咱们应该查一查
I'm just saying we should look into it.
不用
No, we shouldn't.
如果你认为豪斯得病了
If you believe House is sick,
只可能是因为他想让你有这样的想法
it's only because that's what he wants you to believe.
走吧
Let's go.
我们认为长途飞行可导致你的下肢
We think the long flight home allowed clots
形成血栓
to form in your leg.
把这药吃了
Take this pill.
如果过几分钟你的腿有麻木感
If you feel any numbness in your leg after a few minutes,
那我们的诊断就对了  你也可以舒服一阵了
it means we're right and you should get comfortable,
因为你还得在这待一段时间
because you're gonna be here for a while.
既然要等
While we wait,
你能告诉我你为什么这么做吗
can you tell me why?
因为那么做是正确的
It was the right thing to do.
有报道称有反叛分子在利用你的视频
There are reports that insurgents are using your video
召集更多的成员
to recruit new members.
让有投票权的大众知道
Making the voting public aware
战场上到底发生了些什么事
of what's really happening on the ground
能让我们的战友更快地回家
will help bring our troops home faster.
我哥哥叹气是因为他不同意
My brother's grunt means he disagrees.
我认为你很天真
I think you're being naive.
我知道你起过誓
And I know you took an oath.
如果你想改变政策  那就要从政
If you want to influence policy, run for office.
爸爸教过我们  揭示真相是光荣之事
Dad raised us to believe that exposing the truth is honorable.
海耶斯喜欢循规蹈矩
Hayes likes to follow the rules.
对  因为那才是爸爸教导的光荣行为
Yeah, because that's what dad taught us was honorable.
爸爸死时你才十岁
You were ten when he died.
你不可能知道...
You couldn't possibly have any idea--
如果爸爸一直盲目从命
If dad always believe in blindly following the rules,
怎么解释他在托拉博拉之战中的表现
how do you explain Tora Bora?
我爸爸负责指挥一个特种部队作战单元
My dad was commanding a special forces unit.
他与下属失去了联系
He lost communication with his men.
他们被认定已经死亡
They were assumed dead.
他接到命令要放弃他们
He was ordered to abandon them
继续执行首要任务
and focus on the primary mission.
他抗命不遵
He disobeyed that order,
找到了下属  发现他们还活着  抗争着
went and found his men still alive and fighting.
他救了他们的命
He saved their lives.
他是战死的吗
Did he die in service?
如果是因为遗传病  可以帮助我们诊断
If it was something genetic, it could help us.
我爸爸的死因和这没关系
It won't help.
他是车祸死的
It was a one-car accident.
那是军方的官话
That's the army's official story.
我哥哥一直天真地以为...
My brother's naive on this and...
我的腿没有知觉了
I can't feel my leg.
我去拿出院表
I'll get the discharge papers.
我有血栓
I have a blood clot.
不  你没有
No, you don't.
我们给你用的是安慰剂
We gave you a placebo
来看看你是否会装出另外一种症状
to see if you'd fake another symptom
来延缓入狱时间
to delay going to prison.
等等  他不会装病
Wait a second. He's not faking.
因为你们的爸爸没有教他装病吗
Because that's not the way your dad raised him?
对
Yes.
我肚子也疼
My stomach hurts too.
到底怎么回事
What's going on?
他不是装的
He's not faking.
就因为他腹部真有挫伤
Just because he's got abdominal bruising
也不意味着他没有在装麻木感
doesn't mean he wasn't faking the numbness.
他没有就叛国罪的指控进行狡辩
He's not contesting the treason charges.
如果他的荣誉感那么强
If his code of honor is that strong,
他是不会装病的
he's not gonna bother faking symptoms.
认罪可不光荣
Pleading guilty is not honorable.
只是犯傻
It's just stupid.
远端食管破裂可致
A distal esophageal rupture can lead to
他大腿部的骨筋膜室综合征
compartment syndrome in his thigh,
解释了他的两种症状
explains both symptoms.
无吞咽疼痛
No pain when he swallows.
什么是荣誉
What is honor?
为国赴死吗
Dying for your country?
成绩全优吗
Getting straight As?
掐死自己的女儿
Killing your daughter
因为她竟敢被强奸
because she had the audacity to get raped?
腹主动脉瘤破裂
Ruptured triple-a.
解释不了抽蓄
Doesn't explain the seizures.
胰腺炎
Pancreatitis.
胆石阻塞胰管
Gallstones obstructing his pancreatic duct.
人们将荣誉定义为
People define honor
能让自己有荣誉感的事
As whatever makes them feel honorable.
这种逻辑圈得不出任何结论
It's a circle going nowhere.
不过圆圈本来就是这样
which I guess is what circles do.
做个B超  了解有无胆系梗阻
We'll ultrasound his belly and look for the obstruction.
这张单子需要你的签名
I need your signature on this order.
军方要求福曼保证
The army's leaning on Foreman to make sure
一切都照章办事
this is done by the book.
上次给他治疗时没要签单子
Didn't need an order for his last treatment.
上次的治疗不算治疗
This last treatment wasn't a treatment.
-你伪造一下  -我会的
- Forge it. - I will.
从现在开始
From now on.
但我需要有原始签名才能伪造
But I need the original so I know what to forge.
他开始头晕的时候我们在喝咖啡
We were having coffee when the dizziness started.
商务会谈吗
Business meeting?
约会
Date.
第一次
Our first.
我们在一元商店里认识的
We met at the 98 Cents Store.
当时我们同时要拿同一块奶酪
We were reaching for the same tube of cheese.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
怎么了
Yeah.
我要跟你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
快好了
Just about done.
好消息是  从她节俭的消费习惯
Good news, based on her thrifty shopping habits
以及选择人造奶制品来看
and taste for artificial dairy,
她和你约会明显不是为了钱
she's clearly not a gold digger.
坏消息是
Bad news:
根据他的抠鼻强迫症来看  他是
Based on his rhinotillexomania, he is.
也就是对抠鼻子上瘾
Compulsive addiction to nose-picking.
左鼻孔内有一处损伤
A small cut on the inside of the left nostril
导致海绵窦感染
led to an infection in the cavernous sinus.
很高兴认识你  梅尔
It was very nice meeting you, Mel.
不是这样的
It's not true.
格洛瑞娅  等等
Gloria, wait,
我会改的
I can change.
这是我的工作合同
My PPTH contract.
豪斯在六个月前签的
House signed it six months ago.
这是今天签的
He signed this today.
他的手抖
His hands are unsteady.
考虑到他滥用维柯丁
Given his vicodin abuse,
我认为他患有肝性脑病
I think he has hepatic encephalopathy.
他健忘  心不在焉
He's been forgetful, inattentive.
多米尼卡在尝试新式克尼什馅饼
Dominika's been trying out new knish recipes.
其中一个他吃了不太舒服
One of them didn't agree with him.
睡眠不足可能导致
A little sleep deprivation could account
健忘和心不在焉
for his forgetfulness and inattention.
他摄入太多咖啡因  可能导致手部颤抖
He loads up on caffeine. That explains a jittery hand.
有可能
Maybe.
但如果我是对的  他的肝功能正在衰退
But if I'm right, his liver's in decline.
这是可以治愈的  但如果他不接受治疗
It's curable, but if he doesn't get treatment,
可能会致命
It could actually be fatal.
这种事我见多了
This happens all the time.
为豪斯工作的一个副作用就是
One of the symptoms of working for House--
你会变得十分多疑
you start seeing zebras everywhere.
他什么事都没
There's nothing wrong with him.
豪斯
House.
嘘  有病人呢
Shh. I'm with a patient.
睡眠研究
Sleep study.
你给他下药了
You drugged him?
我又没说他是自愿的
I didn't say the study was voluntary.
我认为你病了
I think you're sick.
因为我在诊所里睡觉吗  我一直如此
What, 'cause I'm sleeping in the clinic like I always do?
反应慢
Slow reaction time.
因为我刚在诊所里睡醒
Because I just woke up from sleeping in the clinic
我一直如此
like I always do.
你健忘
You're forgetful.
抱歉  你刚才说什么
Sorry. What did you say?
你忘了我们约好一起吃午饭
You forgot that we were supposed to have lunch.
我没忘
I didn't forget.
我只是在诊所里睡觉
I was sleeping in the clinic--
我要给你做检查
I'd like to run some tests.
为什么
For what?
你怎么了
Where's this coming from?
肝性脑病
Hepatic encephalopathy.
我看着你年复一年滥用维柯丁伤身
I've watched you destroy your body with vicodin for years.
你的肝能撑这么久真是奇迹
I'm surprised your liver's lasted this long.
我会亲自给你做检查
I'll do the examination myself.
虽然让你捣鼓我的小叮当挺有意思
While having you juggle my jewels sounds interesting,
但是炮友什么的都是浮云
There's no such thing as friends with benefits.
最后总是会尴尬的
It always gets weird.
你外面的朋友们看上去很谨慎
Your friends out there are getting a little handsy.
收到了太多的死亡威胁
Get enough death threats,
他们现在终于把这当一回事了
eventually they start taking them seriously.
一个护航队在库纳尔省外遭袭击
A convoy was hit outside of Kunar Province.
八名美军士兵因此死亡
Eight american soldiers were killed.
军方发言人称
Army spokesperson's claiming that
这是起报复行动  针对被我曝光的事件
it's revenge for the attack that I made public.
他们最好把责任都推卸给我
Better me take the blame than them.
你不认为这是你的过错吗
You don't think you're to blame at all?
你这么认为
And you do.
和所有人一样
Like everyone else.
这种袭击至少需要三天时间准备
A strike like that would take more than three days to plan.
那么下一次可能是你的过错了
So the next one might be your fault?
侧面没什么问题
Lateral view looks good.
如果你那么讨厌军方
If you have such a negative opinion of the army,
为什么要入伍
why did you enlist?
我想知道父亲死亡的真相
I needed to find out what really happened to my dad.
他的服役记录中有两页是伪造的
There were two redacted pages in his service record.
进入情报科是提高我安全权限的
Going into intelligence was the quickest way
最快方法
to up my security clearance.
那你为什么要把视频曝光
Then why would you leak that video?
我工作的一部分是和当地人喝茶聊天
Part of my job was to grab a cup of tea with the locals.
这种面谈是为了让他们更信任我们
The face time is supposed to make them more likely
从而得到更敏感的信息
to trust us with sensitive information,
但他们成了我的朋友
But they became my friends.
如果发生另一起袭击
If there was another attack,
造成平民伤亡
civilian casualties,
而我什么都没做的话
and I had done nothing...
你的脾脏增大了
Your spleen, it's enlarged.
我们要做活检  检查是否...
We should do a biopsy and look for any--
他开始尿血
He's got urinary bleeding.
不只是尿血
Not just urinary.
打电话给血库
Call the blood bank.
他怎么了
What's happening to him?
他的脾脏不再释放血小板
His spleen must be sequestering platelets.
他出血太快
He's bleeding too fast to wait
等不到输血小板
for a platelet infusion.
需要挤压脾脏
We need to squeeze his spleen
来释放他自身的血小板
to release the ones he's got.
通知手术室  我们马上过去
Tell the O.R. We're on our way.
血压在下降
Pressure's dropping.
快好了
Almost there.
血压70/40
Bp's 70 over 40,
他血容量不足
and he's hypovolemic.
血压回升了
Pressure's rising.
开始凝血了
And he's starting to clot.
好消息是我们止住出血了
Good news is we can control the bleeding.
坏消息是
Bad news is...
出血不是主要问题
bleeding's not the problem.
除非脾脏表面本身就凹凸不平
Unless spleens are supposed to be lumpy.
血是止住了  但CT显示
He's clotting, but CT confirms
他有脾结节
splenic nodules.
陶博医生有个有趣的想法
Dr. Taub has an interesting theory.
不  我没有
No, I don't.
你不行吗
You're forfeiting?
因为如果你不能边玩边工作的话
'cause if you can't play the game and work...
髓外血细胞生成
Extramedullary hematopoiesis.
无贫血史
No history of anemia.
她说得对  你是个白痴  再来
She's right. You're an idiot. Try again.
在我们那里  这是作弊
Where I come from, this is called cheating.
你从哪里来  菊花镇吗
Where's that? Stickford-upon-anus?
结核病
TB.
结核菌素试验阴性
PPD's negative.
可能是布鲁...
Could be Bru--
别打断陶博医生
Don't interrupt Dr. Taub.
布鲁杆菌病
Brucellosis.
你刚杀了一家四口
You just took out a family of four.
他们明显是武装分子
They were clearly armed insurgents,
如果有人反对或有异议  他就是叛国分子
and anyone who claims or proves otherwise is a traitor.
没红疹及背痛
No rash or back pain.
病人是个告密者  你替他辩护
You defend the patient for being a whistleblower,
然后攻击他是个有荣誉感的告密者
then attack him for being an honorable whistleblower.
现在你又维护他
Now you defend him for being
因为他是个恶意的有荣誉感的告密者
a maligned, honorable whistleblower?
形容词真有用
Adjectives matter.
讨厌护士  大爱调皮的护士
Hate nurses, love naughty nurses.
陶博  再来
Taub, pitch again.
-我都说了五个了  -该你了
- I've pitched like five-- - It's your turn.
淋巴瘤
Lymphoma.
如果是癌症引起的抽蓄
If cancer caused his seizures,
头颅CT应可见到颅内肿物
we would have seen cerebral masses on his head CT.
-好的  -陶博  再来一个
- Yes! - Taub, pitch again.
马上
Now.
脾脏结节为肉芽肿
The nodules in his spleen were granulomas.
他得了伯克氏肉样瘤
He's got Sarcoidosis!
有反对意见吗
Someone tell him he's wrong.
抱歉  豪斯
Sorry, House.
肉样瘤能解释癫痫发作
Sarcoid does explain the seizures.
以及出现的瘀青
And the bruises.
认输吧  豪斯
Say bye-bye, House.
好耶
Yes!
那就是伯克氏肉样瘤了
Sarcoidosis it is.
用类固醇治疗
Treat with steroids.
然后立马给我回来
Then come right back here,
不把你们累个半死不活
'cause I'm not gonna rest until I've made orphans
我是不会善罢甘休的
of all your virtual children.
豪斯从来没有输过
House never loses.
你没开玩笑吧
Seriously?
他被我打败也算是种病症吗
Me beating House is medically significant?
有可能
It could be.
细微运动控制能力的减退
Reduced fine motor control.
加上他注意力不集中以及肝病性扑动
Add that to inattention and liver flap.
这确实是种病症
It does make sense.
我们得告诉福曼
We have to talk to Foreman.
没必要告诉他
No, we don't.
首先
First of all,
我有能力赢他
because I can beat him in that game.
其次  就算你是对的
And, second, even if you are right,
也没有证据表明
there's no reason to believe
豪斯的判断能力受到了影响
that House's medical judgment is impaired.
这么说我们只能等到他误诊死病人
So we should wait until he kills someone
才能确诊吗
for confirmation?
你真的认为这是个巧合吗
You really think it's a coincidence
治疗一名告密者的同时
that we're treating a whistleblower
我们却合计着要告豪斯的密
and now talking about blowing the whistle on House?
你说得没错
You're right.
反应迟钝  笔迹潦草
Playing dumb, messy signature,
游戏失败
losing a video game...
这一切太难作假了
It's way too complicated to fake.
不  我不要打针
No. I won't take it.
不打这针
Without this injection,
你很可能会因心律不齐而丧命
you could have a fatal arrhythmia.
去告诉马修森少校
Tell Major Mathewson
在他们给我安排电视访谈之前
that I'm not taking any more treatment
我不再接受任何治疗
until they give me a live television interview.
你真的认为他们会答应吗
You can't really think they'll agree to that.
我得让人们知道
People need to know
袭击不是由那盘录像带引起的
the tape's not the reason for that attack.
我得告诉他们我这么做的目的
They need to know why I did this.
那些把你看作是叛徒的人
The people who think you're a traitor
仍会当你是叛徒
will still think you're a traitor,
那些将你视为英雄的人
And the people who think you're a hero
仍将视你为英雄
will still think you're a hero.
传达真相意义重大
The truth makes a difference.
如果老爸还健在  他会哀求你别这么干的
If dad were here, he'd be begging for you not to do this.
如果他健在  他会为我自豪的
If dad were here, he'd be proud of me.
如果这病人死了
The conspiracy theorists are gonna go nuts
阴谋论者会借题发挥的
if the patient dies.
我和他这么说了  但是他告诉我
I told him that, and he told me
就算这样  负面影响
that option is still less damaging
仍然会比给他做访谈来得小
than giving the kid a national platform.
我们现在怎么办呢
So what do we do now?
你去和你兄弟解释
You explain to your brother
他这招玩得过火了
that he overplayed his hand.
这还是于事无补啊
That won't make any difference.
那个傻瓜坚信自己做得没错
The idiot thinks he's doing the right thing.
如果我们让法庭相信他拒绝治疗
What if we convinced a court that his refusal
是源于潜在的精神障碍呢
is part of an underlying psychiatric disorder?
他们指派一个监护人  就是我们说了算了
They assign a conservator. We do what we want.
你这是诈骗  妙啊
Fraud. Great.
自恋型人格障碍
Narcissistic Personality Disorder.
泄露录像以及拒绝治疗
Both the leaking of the tape and the refusal of treatment
都说明他对行为的后果毫不在意
indicate that he has no fear of consequences.
这么说你不准备欺骗法庭了
So instead of defrauding the court,
而是要浪费他们的时间
you'll waste their time?
没有一个法官会把人格障碍
No way a judge classifies a personality disorder
当作是精神疾病处理的
as a mental illness.
如果这一说法被一个军功显赫
If a decorated military officer, who happened
同时又身为病人哥哥的军官证实  法庭可能会相信
to be the patient's brother, corroborates, they might.
这么说你要我签字
So you want me to sign a piece of paper
证明我弟弟是疯子
that says my brother is crazy
就因为他坚持了自己的信念
for doing what he thinks is right?
我想你救他的命
I want you to save his life.
他随时有心律不齐的危险
His heart could go at any time.
他是个傻瓜
He's a fool.
但不是疯子
But he's not crazy.
病人出于荣誉感
The patient was refusing treatment
拒绝治疗  而他哥哥
because of honor, and his brother
出于荣誉感
Is refusing to be his conservator
拒绝当他的监护人
because of honor.
很好
Oh, good.
陶博把病人治好了
Taub's cured the patient.
我上厕所去了
I had to go to the bathroom.
厕所在那个方向  你是从那边走过来的
Bathroom's that way. You just ran in from that way.
那个厕所坏了两天了
That one's been out of order for two days.
我不得不去三楼上
I had to go up to the third floor.
我没骗你
I'm not lying.
是真的坏了
It's out of order.
我相信你  我去修好它
I believe you. I'm gonna fix it.
我们可以在他不知不觉中给他治疗
We could treat if he doesn't know he's being treated.
用药物进行海绵擦浴
Lace his sponge bath.
擦浴见效太慢
It would take too long to reach his bloodstream.
在他房间里喷雾化类固醇呢
What if we aerosolize steroids and blast the room?
这个么...
Speaking of which...
很难控制泼尼松的浓度
It'd be too hard to get the prednisone concentrations right.
如果不给出些气势逼人的理由
No one fixes anything
是不会有人来修马桶的
unless they have a compelling reason.
我们要想医治他的话
If we're gonna treat,
得给他个比采访
we have to give him a compelling reason,
更感兴趣的理由
something that he wants more than an interview.
屎炮攻击
Fire in the hole!
这是马修森少校签署的命令
A signed order from Major Mathewson.
他们同意将你父亲的档案
They've agreed to declassify the redacted pages
进行解密了
from your father's service record.
两天后  你就能得到答案了
In two days, you'll have all your answers.
但是你只有接受治疗
But the only way you'll live long enough to get the truth
才活得到那个时候
is by accepting treatment.
我不相信军队最终会解密
I don't trust the army to follow through on this.
但是你可以相信我
But you trust me.
我会保证那些文件送达这里
I'll make sure those pages get here.
好的
Okay.
现在自私自利也算是荣耀吗
Selfishness is apparently honorable now.
他当初想要做出改变
He wanted to create change.
但现在只是满足自己的好奇心
Instead, he's just satisfying his own curiosity.
他要知道真相了  这是他最大的心愿
He's getting the truth. Most he could hope for.
我去上个大号
I need to take a dump.
确切的说  是去拿豪斯的大号
Specifically, House's dump.
这是你一手策划的吗
You set this up?
我只需要晚到这么一两分钟
All it took was showing up two minutes late
再花两块钱买个牌子
and a $2 sign.
胆汁沉着物不规则
Bile deposits are irregular.
豪斯的肝脏在衰竭
House's liver is failing.
认知缺损会渐进性恶化
Cognitive impairment will get progressively worse.
怎么了
What's going on?
我的脚
My foot.
疼死我了
It's killing me.
它完全发绀了
It's completely cyanotic.
这不是伯克氏肉样瘤
This isn't Sarcoidosis.
胆固醇栓塞
Cholesterol Embolization.
我们前面和你说的  你到底承认不承认
Are you gonna even acknowledge what we just told you?
你们偷了我的大便
That you pilfered my poo-poo?
我想如果我们大家假装这事儿没发生过
Yeah, I was thinking it would be less awkward
也许就不会这么尴尬了
for all of us if we could just pretend that never happened.
这不是栓塞
It's not an embolization.
动脉内无固定物
No instrumentation inside the arteries.
谢谢你言归正传
Thank you for getting us back.
如果现在开始对你进行治疗的话
And if we start you on treatment now,
让你戒断维柯丁
Get you off vicodin.
"谢谢你"的反义词是什么啊
What's the opposite of "Thank you"?
我记得是和你妈有关的三字短语
I'm pretty sure it ends in "You".
我的身体我了解  我很好
I know my body. I'm fine.
高铁血红蛋白血症
Methemoglobinemia.
军队里检查过葡萄糖-6-磷酸脱氢酶缺乏症
Army tests for G6PD Deficiency.
如果你没有病
If you're not sick,
就是说这个精度高达99.5%的检测
then our test, accurate 99.5% of the time,
分别三次出现假阳性
yielded a false positive three separate times.
这个可能仅为八百万分之一
The odds of that are 1 in 8 million.
你们的检测没有错  是诊断出错了
The test is accurate. The diagnosis isn't.
显然  样本受到了其他食物的污染
Sample was obviously contaminated with other foods
与我的肝脏酶互相影响
interacting with my liver enzymes.
我们能谈谈病人了吗
Now could we talk about the sick patient?
他的血凝块溶解了
His clot dissolved.
这能够导致血管痉挛
That could have caused the vasospasm.
弥漫性血管内凝血可以由伯-苏综合征引起
D.I.C. could have been caused by bernard soulier syndrome.
你病了
And you're sick,
你得想想办法啊
and you have to do something about it.
如果我们有个病例
If we had a patient file with the same symptoms
表现出和你相同的症状
you're exhibiting...
还有我没表现出来的症状
And the symptoms I'm not exhibiting?
黄疸 腹水 肝病性口臭
Jaundice, ascites, fetor hepaticus.
我们无法得知你是否口臭
We can't tell if your breath stinks
因为你一直像嗑药似的吃薄荷糖
because you've been popping mints like they're vicodin.
你仍然被诊断为肝性脑病
You'd still diagnose hepatic encephalopathy.
因为你培养出的四个医生
I know that because four doctors you trained
一致认为你得的是这个病
have unanimously diagnosed you with hepatic encephalopathy.
朴克说得没错
Park's right.
给病人用肝素治疗
Treat the patient with heparin.
如果我们四人一起去和福曼说
We'll have a stronger argument
比较容易说动他
if we go to foreman as a united front.
我们各有争论才有说头
We'll have a stronger argument if we have an argument.
就算豪斯病了  那也是他的事  跟福曼无关
If House is sick, it's his business, not Foreman's.
福曼的工作就是确保他手下的医生
Foreman's business is to make sure his doctors
能正常行医  不危及病人的生命
are able to do their jobs, that lives aren't put at risk.
告诉福曼才会殃及病人
Telling Foreman will put lives at risk.
那样做  豪斯要么接受治疗
We tell Foreman, House either agrees to treatment
要么被停职  都意味着他不能行医
or get suspended, which means House gets suspended.
考虑到他有所保留
And considering House at 90%
都要好过这家医院任何使劲全力的医生
is better than any other doctor at this hospital at 100%,
少了他  病人将会得到较低水平的医疗照顾
that meansur patients get a lower standard of care.
豪斯是有所保留  或是状态欠佳
House could be at 90%, he could be at 60%,
我们拿捏不准
we don't know.
那在确定之前
And until we do, there's no reason
我们就按兵不动
to do anything more than what we've done.
视物模糊
Blurry vision...
头痛  有点恶心  还有头晕
headache, a bit of nausea, and dizziness.
我完全被难住了
I am completely baffled.
我喝了八瓶啤酒而已
I only had eight beers.
二年级啤酒乒乓球赛就在下周
Sophomore class pong tournament's in a week.
我在练酒量
I'm working on my tolerance.
单脚跳  唱《爱卡莉》主题曲
Hop on one foot and sing the iCarly Theme Song.
别一副你不知道的表情
Like you don't know it.
*我心确定  你会看到*
*I know, you see*
*世界将为我改变*
*Somehow the world will change for me*
*精彩纷呈*
*And be so wonderful*
*活在当下  呼吸空气*
*Live life, breathe air*
真是的  伙计  你没看到我在会诊吗
Damn it, man. Can't you see I'm doctoring?
*我们会到达那世外桃源*
*We're gonna get there and be so wonderful*
如果想和我聊天
If you want to talk to me,
你可以在一小时后给我买个三明治
you can buy me a sandwich in an hour.
我也可以杵在这里等你会诊结束
Or I could just hover here until you're done.
*这些*
*These--*
够了
Heard enough.
一直想不起来"呼吸空气"这句
Just never could figure out the "Breathe air" part.
明年  拿威士忌练
Next year, stick to whiskey.
至少别再喝一周陈的新啤酒了
Or at least stay away from week-old green beers.
威士忌少有添加你不耐的
A lot less likely to contain tartrazine-laced green food dyes
酒石黄绿色食品染料
for which you apparently have an intolerance.
而且一旦开尿
Once you break the seal,
48小时内就能排出体外
it'll be out of your system in 48 hours.
我有的选吗
What are my choices here?
我跟你说我没事吧
If I tell you I'm fine,
你不会信我
you won't believe me.
我安排了肝功能测试
I've scheduled a liver function test.
我无视你吧  你就直接无视我的无视
If I ignore you, then you'll just ignore my ignoring.
老实说  挺没礼貌的
Which is rude, frankly.
根据测试结果
Depending on the results,
我们再制定治疗计划
we'll customize a treatment plan.
要是我跟你说我觉得自己病了需要你的帮助
If I tell you I think I'm sick and I need your help
需要找个时间聊一聊
and we need to set up a time to talk about it,
你会以为我在撒谎
you'll just assume I'm lying.
依旧无礼  还很伤人
Again, rude. Also hurtful.
你能找到别人身上最细微的差错
Why is it that you can find the smallest thing wrong
可换作是你自己  怎么就
with anyone else, but when it comes to you...
我是真的没有选择的余地  你说呢
I really don't have a choice here, do I?
确实
No, you don't.
我在名单上  他没有
I'm on the list. But he's not.
躲得了初一  躲不过十五
You can't ignore me forever.
如果你说得对  那也用不了那么久
Well, if you're right, that's not gonna be all that long.
慢慢来
Do it slow.
你是谁
Who are you?
允许进入这间病房的
Well, considering the only people allowed
只有你的医生和家人
in this room are your doctors and your family...
我是你失散多年的表兄拉尔夫
I'm your long-lost cousin Ralph.
很高兴终于见到你了
So glad to finally meet you.
你要给我做检查吗
Are you gonna check on me?
至少要两小时
It's gonna be at least two hours
我们才能知道肝素是否起作用
until we can tell if the heparin's working.
那你来这里干什么
Then what are you doing here?
我父亲教导我
You know, my father taught me that it's dishonorable
不以烦扰他人阅读为荣
to interrupt someone when they're reading.
荣誉不是戏话
Honor's not a punch line.
出去
Get out of my room.
你那样做值得吗
So was it worth it?
最好的结果  你余生都将在莱文沃思的监狱里度过
Best case, you spend the rest of your life in Leavenworth.
最糟的结果  你就一直待在这里了
Worst case, you spend the rest of your life here.
为34名死者伸张正义比军队对我的处理更重要
Justice for 34 deaths outweighs anything the army can do to me.
他们得到公正了吗
They got justice?
他们知道吗
Do they know that?
如果只有十名死者呢
What if only ten people had died?
或者四名
Four?
只要有一名平民遇害
Even one civilian death...
如果他们只是受伤致残了呢
What if they just maimed a few guys?
还值得吗
Would that have been worth it?
我的工作是记录录像内容
My job was to log that tape,
把所有细节录入官方
get all the details in the official record.
看第十遍之后
After the tenth time of watching it,
我停止说服自己
I stopped trying to convince myself
可能是铲子被误认为了枪
that the shovel could have been mistaken for a gun.
我只看得到受害者的脸
'cause all I could see were the victims' faces.
我试图阅读那孩子的嘴唇
All I was doing was trying to read that kid's lips
以辨别他最后说的话
to make out his last words.
我睡不着
I couldn't sleep.
吃不下
Couldn't eat.
你以为我喜欢光着头吗
Think I like the cue ball look?
我的黑发三天变灰发
My hair turned gray in three days.
我的身体在告诉我  我必须尽我所能
My body was telling me I had to do whatever I could
确保此类事件
to make sure that something like this
不再发生
never happened again.
你三天黑发变灰发
Your hair turned gray in three days.
头发褪色表明是自身免疫性疾病
Loss of hair color indicates an autoimmune condition,
可能是毒性弥漫性甲状腺肿
likely Grave's disease.
甲状腺机能亢进会导致血液高凝状态
Hyperthyroidism leads to a hypercoagulable state,
从而导致血栓
which causes thrombosis.
给他用抗甲状腺药
Start him on antithyroids.
你驳回我们当前的诊断
You want to reject our current diagnosis
就因为他有几根灰头发
because he had a few gray hairs,
绝望恐慌  剃了光头
panicked, and shaved his head?
我否定我们当前的诊断
I want to reject our current diagnosis
是因为我觉得我们弄错了
because I think we're wrong.
不对症确诊
And treating for wrong diagnoses
会引起死亡这类副作用
can result in side effects like death.
就算他头发全变灰了
Even if he did full go gray,
这更像是应激状态
stress seems way more likely than Grave's.
我还没读到过任何文献
I haven't read any journal articles
是证明老兵头发褪色的几率更高的
proving that veterans have a higher incidence of depigmentation.
当然这也有可能是肝性脑病导致的
Of course, that could be the hepatic encephalopathy talking.
我们针对伯-苏综合征的治疗还没时间
Our treatment for Bernard Soulier hasn't had time--
所以你们都打算忽略新症状吗
So you all just want to ignore the new symptom?
那不是格雷夫斯病  因为头发变灰根本不是症状
It's not Grave's because it's not a symptom at all.
你想用的抗甲状腺药会降低他的血压
And the antithyroids you want could reduce his blood pressure
和他呼吸的能力
and his ability to breathe.
从而引起死亡  这类的副作用
Which can result in side effects, like death.
小杯汽水
Small soda.
就是毒性弥漫性甲状腺肿
Grave's it is.
给他用抗甲状腺药
Start him on antithyroids.
我知道我们向来和豪斯意见不符
I know we disagree with House all the time,
但以前我会说  好吧  他是个天才
but, before I could say, "Okay, he's a genius."
现在  可能他只是很聪明而已
Now...maybe he's just really smart.
我们不给他用抗甲状腺药
We're not gonna give him the antithyroids.
一切都好吗
Everything okay?
感觉好些吗
Any better?
还不错
Pretty good.
他问我要了条毯子
He did just ask me for a blanket.
你冷吗
You're cold?
有一点
A little.
多久了
For how long?
没什么的
It's really nothing.
可能一两个小时吧
Maybe an hour or two.
他有40摄氏度
He's at 104.
不是伯-苏综合征
It's not Bernard Soulier.
大胆  你们从推测我病了
Bold move. You've gone from speculating
进步到行动时当我死了
that I'm sick to acting like I'm dead.
我们的行为出于不相信你的判断
We acted like we don't trust your judgment,
因为我们不相信你的判断
because we don't trust your judgment.
不如先别相信你们自己的判断
Why don't you start by not trusting your own?
我们做了更多的血检
We did more blood work.
也不是毒性弥漫性甲状腺肿
It's not Grave's either.
能跟你说几句吗
Talk to you for a minute?
你想跟我说的也可以跟他们说
Anything you have to say to me you can say to them.
这样才公平  因为他们跟我说的
It's only fair, 'cause anything they say to me,
也跟你说了
they also say to you.
抖抖口袋  谁是家贼
Jiggle your pockets. Who's got the silver coins?
在你收到健康证明书前
Until you receive a Clean Bill Of Health,
由我主持治疗
I'll be authorizing all treatment orders.
我想说这是一个极其愚蠢的错误决定
Well, I would say that that was an incredibly stupid mistake,
但显然我得先向福曼
but apparently I'd have to clear that opinion
报备这个观点才行
through Foreman first.
白细胞计数高
White count is high.
所以他入院时我们排除的感染
So all the infections we ruled out
重新列入考虑范围
when he came in are back on the table.
军团病
Legionnaire's.
没有肺炎  不太可能
Unlikely without pneumonia.
陶博
Taub.
个人生活的忠诚问题
Loyalty issues in his personal life.
能够解释你在职业生涯中的告密行为
Makes sense that they'd cross over into his professional one.
我希望在政治迫害前
I was hoping we can get a diagnosis
得出诊断结果
before the witch hunt.
病人的感染
The patient's infection
怎么比得上我被放冷箭
is an inherently less interesting puzzle
来得有意思呢
than the stab wound to my back.
行吧  是我告诉福曼的
Fine. I told Foreman.
可以继续了吗
Can we move on now?
会不会是登革热
What about dengue?
病人并未经历剧烈疼痛
Patient isn't in enough pain.
不对
No.
我指的不是登革热  我不清楚
I don't mean about dengue. I have no idea.
陶博站出来承认不过是想让我们
Taub's only confessing because he wants us
继续关注病人
to focus on the patient.
是我告诉的福曼
I told Foreman.
是我
I did.
下一个出来自首的被解雇了
The next person to confess is fired.
或者是斯巴达克斯
Or Spartacus.
我声明  不会解雇任何人
For clarification, no one's getting fired.
还谁有想法
Who else has a pitch?
现在只剩下朴克了
And then...there's Park.
只有一个人没自首
The only one who didn't confess.
因为胆怯不敢搬出父母家
The same cowardice that makes someone unable
单独住的人
to move out of mommy and daddy's home
也很可能是个告密者
might also make someone a tattletale.
你威胁说要解雇下一个自首的
You threatened to fire the next person who...
是疟疾
And it's malaria.
不  不是
No, it's not.
军方有针对疟疾的医疗计划
The army issues anti-malaria medication.
那是十年前了
And has done for ten years.
十年间阿富汗蚊和冈比亚按蚊
That's the equivalent of 5,000 generations
已经繁衍了五千代
of the Afghan mosquito, anopheles gambiae.
足以产生抗性了
That's plenty long enough to develop a resistance.
疟蚊在希腊语里正是"无能"的意思
Anopheles, by the way, is Greek for "Useless."
不排除腹腔感染  用抗疟疾药治疗
Cover for intra-abdominal sepsis and treat with antimalarials.
我说你来插手很愚蠢也是对的吧
And was I also right that it was a stupid idea?
我们认为你患了疟疾
We believe you have malaria.
这些药
These pills...
我不想服用药物
I don't want any medication.
我爸爸的档案该到了
My dad's file should have been here.
布兰特  我跟你说过  我有去问
Brant, I told you, I looked into it.
不过是耽搁了
There's just a delay.
我相信这是军方的说法
I believe that's what the army's saying.
但我不相信他们说的是真的
I don't believe it's true.
如果他们不打算守约
If they're not going to keep their end of the bargain,
我也不
neither am I.
我们白白被搜了那么多遍身
So we got groped for nothing.
要是他自己不打算活下去...
If he doesn't want to stay alive...
等等
Hold on.
现在做他的监护人还来得及吗
Is it too late to become his conservator?
我知道自己之前说过什么
I know what I said before.
我现在不在乎了
Right now I don't care.
当然不晚
Of course not.
我们这就去准备文书
We'll get the paperwork drawn up.
他改主意了
He changed his mind?
为什么
Why?
他弟弟就要死了
His brother's dying.
他还需要更充分的理由吗
He needs a more substantial reason?
我们上一次要他做监护人
His brother was dying the last time
他弟弟也在生死边缘
we asked him to be the conservator.
所以他不去催促军方要档案
So instead of pushing the issue with the army
反而放弃了自己坚持的原则
to get the file, he just decided to give up on his code?
显然如此
Apparently.
哪里签字
So where do I sign?
不需要签字
We don't need you to.
军方昨天已经把档案给你了
The army gave the file to you yesterday.
马修森少校给我们又发了一份
Major Mathewson had another copy sent over to us.
其实我不想这份档案公布是有原因的
You know, there's a reason I didn't want that file released.
我知道  我读过了
I know. I read it.
我现在要去给病人治病了
I'm gonna treat my patient now.
我是对的
I was right.
是不是
Wasn't I?
他是怎么死的
How did he die?
他们隐藏了什么
What did they cover up?
他们没有隐藏真相
They didn't cover up anything.
是我
I did.
老爸会丧生车祸是因为他醉酒
Dad died in that car accident because he was drunk.
还撞死一名行人
Killed a pedestrian too.
你说什么...  什么
What are you-- what--
他酗酒  布兰特  很严重
He drank, Brant, a lot.
你当时太小不知道
You were too young to see it.
所以我就托老爸的战友
I, uh, I had some of dad's buddies...
帮忙把他的档案保密
take care of his files.
那是我唯一一次违反纪律
It was the only time I ever broke the rules.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我可以开始治疗了吗
Can I begin treatment?
发热依然不退
Fever hasn't broken.
白细胞计数未减
White count is still up.
肾功能正在下降
Renal function is declining.
他有疟疾的所有症状
So he has all the signs of malaria,
抗疟疾药却无效
except the antimalarials aren't curing him.
淋病
Gonorrhea?
如果发展到心脏...
If it got into his heart...
我们做了超声  他的瓣膜都是好的
We did an echo. His valves look good.
会不会
What about...
你这混蛋
You bastard.
你都是装的
You were faking.
昨天豪斯用饮料杯偷糖果
Yesterday, House stole candy by putting it into a cup.
杯子太小装不下
The cup was too small, so his solution
他就拿出去些
was to remove some of the candy.
但更合理的方法显然是换个大杯
But the obviously logical thing was to just get a bigger cup,
他今天换了  因为他不再装病
which he did today, because he's no longer faking.
那不可能是装出来的  我们化验了你的...
He couldn't have faked it. We tested your...
我服了圣约翰草
I took St. John's wort to alter the way
以改变肝脏代谢乙酰氨基酚的方式
my liver metabolized acetaminophen.
又加了一些N-乙酰半胱氨酸完善效果
Then some n-acetylcysteine just to finish it off.
你害得他们来折磨我
You tortured them to torture me
就为了看看哪个人可信
just to see who you could trust?
我是为了挽救生命
I did it to save lives.
天哪  说得更合理些就完美了
God, I wish I could rationalize that one.
现在你又要奇迹般地推理出
And now you're going to brilliantly deduce
我们哪一个是告密者了
which one of us is the rat?
你怎知我不是已经猜到了
What makes you think I haven't already?
此事再议
To be continued.
我要去奇解疑症了
I need to brilliantly cure a patient.
通常来说  没头发就没虱子
No hair usually means no lice.
我们没想到的是  你没毛发其他生物有
What we didn't account for was that it wasn't your hair.
你的阿富汗邻居与你分享的可不只是茶
Tea was not the only thing that your Afghani neighbors shared with you.
我想他们慷慨待客
I'm sure they were generous enough
一定请你在家里坐了
to let you sit on their furniture,
家具被老鼠身上的虱子污染
which was infested with rat lice.
你得的是斑疹伤寒
You have typhus.
伤寒引起脉管炎以及你的所有症状
Caused the vasculitis and explains all your other symptoms.
不过最有趣的是
But here's where it gets interesting.
你的律师可以辩称
One of those symptoms, a lawyer might argue,
泄露录像也是病症之一
was leaking the tape.
斑疹伤寒可能引发精神问题
There are psychiatric issues associated with typhus.
如果你改变主意
If you change your mind,
辩称无罪
plead not guilty,
还是有机会的
you've got a case.
那等于一手毁掉我之前坚持的事情
I'd be undermining everything I've been trying to do.
你认为正确的事情你已经做了
You did what you thought you had to do.
坐牢什么都不能证明
Going to jail proves nothing.
可以证明我仍然有荣誉
It proves I still have my honor.
你这样做不是为了荣誉
You're not doing this for honor.
而是为了取悦你父亲
You're doing this to please your father.
悲剧在于你费尽心机要取悦的人
And the pathetic thing is that the man
他从未存在过
you're trying to please never existed.
叛徒
Traitor.
你躲了我两天
You've been avoiding me for two days.
因为被我阻截之后
'cause, when I stranded you behind the barricades,
你直接跑去找了福曼
you went straight to Forman.
我躲你是因为你是个混蛋
I've been avoiding you because you're an ass.
我这辈子一直这样混  甩你都甩不掉
I've been an ass my whole life. I can't get rid of you.
现在甩得掉了
You can get rid of me now.
转身拐着出去就好
Just turn and limp away.
你义正词严的牢骚有股诚实的恶臭
Your whiny righteousness has the stench of sincerity.
好吧  我只好去惩罚所有组员
Fine. I have to punish my whole team
好让犯事的站出来
So that one of them will step forward.
有道理
Makes sense.
该死
Damn.
现在我只好去惩罚所有组员
Now I'm gonna have to punish my whole team
好让犯事的站出来
so that one of them will step forward.
你刚刚说过了
You just said that.
对  可这一次我是当真的
Yeah, but I meant it this time.
上一次只是为了试你
First time I was just testing you.
你要么会真的承认
Either you were gonna genuinely confess
要么假装承认
or falsely confess
又或者...
or actually...
他叫奇小斯
His name's li'l Chase.
他是老鼠
He's a rat.
你是家贼
You're a rat.
懂了吗
Get it?
陶博承认告密是为了保护病人
Taub confessed to telling Forman to protect the patient.
亚当斯自首是为了保护陶博
Adams confessed to protect Taub.
而你的自首完全是跟风
But your confession was just piling on.
你的行为缺乏合理的解释
There's no rational reason for you to have done it.
而我的惩罚会是...  没有惩罚
And my punishment will be nothing.
你想要我告诉福曼
You wanted me to tell Forman.
你唯一在意的
Your ability to solve puzzles
就是自己参透谜题的能力
Is the only thing that matters to you.
而你也足够明智
And you're smart enough to know
知道一旦有一天你失控了
even you'll lose your edge at some point,
必须保证有人可以接任
you want to make sure someone's there when you do.
如果你说得对
If that were true,
为什么奇小斯的小兄弟们
Why are li'l Chase's li'l cousins
正在你家地板上撒欢呢
scurrying through your apartment's floorboards right now?